When the mission ends, redemption begins
Extraction is a action, thriller film directed by Sam Hargrave.
A hardened gun-for-hire's latest mission becomes a soul-searching race to survive
when he's sent into Bangladesh to rescue a drug lord's kidnapped son.
Tyler Rake, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Ovi Mahajan, played by Rudhraksh Jaiswal.
Saju, played by Randeep Hooda.
Nik Khan, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
Ovi Mahajan Sr., played by Pankaj Tripathi.
Gaspar, played by David Harbour.
Extraction is a 2020 American action thriller film directed by Sam Hargrave and
written by Joe Russo, based on the 2014 graphic novel Ciudad.
It is the first installment in the Extraction franchise.
The film stars Chris Hemsworth, Rudhraksh Jaiswal, Randeep Hooda,
Golshifteh Farahani, Pankaj Tripathi and David Harbour.
In the film, an Australian mercenary takes on a mission to save an Indian drug lord's kidnapped
son in Dhaka, Bangladesh, but the mission goes awry when he is double-crossed.
Development of the film began in 2018.
The Russo brothers, who were part of the writing team on Ciudad, had
always intended to adapt the novel for the screen.
Netflix released Extraction on April 24, 2020.
It received mixed reviews and became the most-watched original film in Netflix's
history, with over 99 million viewers during the first four weeks.
A sequel, Extraction 2, was released in 2023, with the main cast returning.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, mercenary, crime
boss, mumbai (bombay), india, rescue mission.
The tone is intense.